<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Diya Bhat</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Diya Bhat</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 1 (Exploratory Data Analysis)</title>
      <link>/project1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project1/</guid>
      <description>Exploring the Minimum Wage and Housing Market in the United StatesIntroduction: Two major predictors of the health of the US economy have always consistently been the housing market prices and the wage levels. I found two very interesting datasets, both on Kaggle. The first is a data set of US state and federal minimum wages from 1968 to 2017 per state and county, collected by the US Department of Labor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 2</title>
      <link>/project2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project2/</guid>
      <description>Modeling the Important Factors that Contribute to Historical Mass Conflicts0. Introduction: Throughout history, we have seen wars and conflicts of varying scale. From the Civil War 1865 to WWI starting in 1914, we have seen schisms root from a multitude of reasons. Our inability to determine which exact factors predict the coming of a war, puts us in an eternal state of peril because we do not know how to avoid what we cannot identify as a direct causation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/</guid>
      <description>Projects Here are some projects I have been working on:
Project 1
Project 2</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python in R</title>
      <link>/blog/pythoninr/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/pythoninr/</guid>
      <description>One incredible advantage of using R-Markdown is its ability as a platform to be compatible with tons of languages apart from R such as: Python, SQL, Javascript, CSS, and more. R is a powerful tool, but sometimes the need arises to use a different language like Python, that is faster and contains packages that might not be available in R.Here, we explore how to use Python on R-Markdown and an introduction to Python basics.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>